

JIBRIL Abdurrashid

AWS Cloud / DevOps / Middleware Engineer

I offer over 16 years of experience working with top financial services firms building and managing revenue generating customer offerings. Hands on subject matter expert with exposure to various infrastructures from service operations in a data center to collaborating with application architects around the world in service design. A constant curiosity has led me carry multiple certifications across several disciplines throughout my career from an operating system, project management, process improvement to public cloud providers.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TIAA 05/2015 - 10/2016

Senior Engineer

Utilize ITIL Service Operations, Service Transition, and Continual Service Improvement knowledge to lead cross-functional global vendor managed services second level 24/7 team to ensure that 197 internal & external facing products are available in production and development stages on traditional and cloud infrastructures.

- Review and assign change requests as part of the firm wide monthly enterprise release cycle with automation of deployments to WebLogic, Webshpere, and Tomcat J2EE application servers.
- Key member of improvement project to upgrade all WebLogic data sources to Oracle Active GridLink configurations to improve High Availability.
- Collaborate with Release Management on the evaluation and implementation of scheduled enterprise releases to ensure that manual tasks have been vetted, approved, and assigned.

J.P. Morgan 01/2007 - 05/2015

11/2013 - 05/2015 VP TechOps Lead

Perform monthly Service Reviews for Platform as a Service management, which detail customer footprints, Capacity, Risk Control Self Assessment scorecard, Change Management, Incident volumes, and Business Process Index.

- Implemented procedures to identify data quality issues that were significantly impacting our key Business Process Index metric and to influence Service Operations leaders to implement service improvements to ensure our service exceeds the 99.90% expected uptime.
- Represent PaaS in weekly meetings with various external Risk, Vulnerability, Resiliency, and Service Operations teams to analyze service metrics and progress on initiatives.
- Drive the collaboration with Risk team on Risk Control Self Assessments, Audit Action plans, and Vulnerability management to ensure that my team provides accurate substantiation and resolves any potential threats.

VP Engineering Lead 12/2011 - 10/2013

Managed a small team of Middleware Subject Matter Experts in a DevOps environment to ensure that our JPM Access Portal application is available to approximately 50,000 users across the globe.

- Responsible for Problem Ownership and Root Cause analysis on all Web Middleware infrastructure incidents escalated to my team via HP Service Manager. Collaborate with Vendors, Service Delivery, System Administration, Database Administration, and other infrastructure teams to find resolutions to complex application issues.
- Responsible for reviewing, approving, and resource allocation for all planned Middleware implementations via a BMC Remedy IT Service Management (ITSM) corporate wide change management approval process.

Jersey City, NJ



(917) 496-7839



info@pioggia.cloud

EDUCATION

B.Sc., Computer Information Systems Baruch College - CUNY, 2000

SKILLS

Amazon Web Service: Route53, ELB, VPC, EC2, S3, EBS, AWS CLI, IAM, CloudFormation

DevOps: Jenkins, Ansible, Docker, Git, Maven, Serena Business Manager, Borland StarTeam, SVN

Middleware Services: Apache 2.x, Oracle WebLogic 12c/11g, Tomcat 7/8, WebSphere 9/8

Security Services: IBM WebSphere DataPower XI50, Barracuda Web Application Firewall, Juniper Secure Access (SA), Netcontinuum Application Security Gateway, SiteMinder 6.0, SSL

Applications: ServiceNow, Confluence, JIRA, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint, Bash, Python, HP Service Manager, BMC Remedy IT Service Management (ITSM), SharePoint, Magic, SiteScope, NetBackup

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Change Management
- Service Delivery
 - Risk and Control Self Assessment
- Problem Ownership
- Continuous Improvement

JIBRIL Abdurrashid

AWS Cloud / DevOps / Middleware Engineer

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE - Continued

J.P. Morgan

AVP Web Engineer 01/2007 - 11/2011

Provide Web Middleware Subject Matter Expertise to Application Development Architects to build enterprise applications that are critical to the success of the firm on a global scale. The collaboration includes project implementation, security, capacity planning, performance tuning, vendor engagement, and root cause analysis.

- Utilized proven PRINCE2 Practitioner project management techniques to lead multiple middleware project types that range from new enterprise technologies to quarterly application enhancements.
- Wrote application specific technical documentation for off shore Follow The Sun Support personnel, which details all web middleware infrastructure components of the product and proven trouble shooting techniques.

Credit Suisse 11/2003 - 11/2006

Technical Specialist 01/2005 - 11/2006

Project Lead, designed, configured, and managed business critical web application infrastructure for Equities, Fixed Income, and Asset Management divisions within Credit Suisse.

- Configured J2EE & .NET applications to utilize Sun One or IIS 6 web servers, WebLogic 8.1 application servers, Cisco GSS & CSS load balancing, and Siteminder identity management.
- Documented web product infrastructure, detailing application components with graphical load balancing configurations, business continuity plan, content management, and proven troubleshooting techniques. This documentation was the primary tool used by second level support to troubleshoot the application.

Technical Analyst II 11/2003 - 12/2004

Mitigated operational risks that were the result of failed internal processes, systems, or components in the global production application infrastructure.

- Responsible for high availability n-tier Internet E-Commerce web applications comprised of iPlanet & IIS web servers, application servers, middleware messaging, and relational databases.
- Identified unexpected exceptions in web and application server logs to determine if the exceptions were the result of application or infrastructure deficiencies.

Thomson Reuters 10/2000 - 10/2003

Systems Operator

Provide Incident Management for web applications, server hardware, operating systems, network components, and data management for business units within Thomson Reuters in order to minimize any downtime for our clients.

- Applied skills achieved from SUN Solaris 8 Certification to provide second level UNIX administration and support to Production, Quality Assurance, and Development environments, which resulted in a 20% decrease in escalated issues to the UNIX administration team.
- Ensured data resiliency through automated system backups configured in VERITAS NetBackup and achieved a successful completion rate of 99%. Engaged off-site document management vendor to schedule storage and data recovery.
- > Created a Korn Shell script to consolidate departmental-wide monitoring stations.

REFERENCES

Julia Kulbanskiy, Executive Director J.P. Morgan Julia.Kulbanskiy@jpmorgan.com Hari Chittepu, Manager TIAA Harip.Chittepu@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS









INTEREST / ACTIVITIES



Trail Running



Snow Boarding

SOCIAL MEDIA

in linkedin.com/in/jibril

